<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quantum-Thermodynamics Hub</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/</link><atom:link href="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Quantum-Thermodynamics Hub</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2026 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/media/logo_huc9fb04e7690501d295d4a3460915f0ea_36726_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Quantum-Thermodynamics Hub</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/</link></image><item><title>Maryland Quantum-Thermodynamics Hub</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quantum thermodynamics is an emerging field that offers fundamental
insights into energy, information, and their relationship. Thermodynamics
originally described classical systems—everyday objects formed from
many particles. The theory has recently extended to the quantum domain
of single electrons and few atoms, which behave in ways impossible for
everyday objects. For example, quantum particles correlate strongly
through entanglement, which gives one particle a surprisingly large amount
of information about others. Scientists are leveraging such quantum
phenomena in technologies such as quantum computers. We combine
mathematical and conceptual tools from quantum physics, information
processing, and thermodynamics to understand how everyday phenomena
—our classical world and the flow of time—emerge from microscopic
quantum physics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From 2022 to 2025, the Maryland Quantum-Thermodynamics Hub
addressed thermodynamic emergence from three angles: (1) How quickly
does entanglement dissipate? (2) How similar is entanglement’s dissipation
to time’s arrow? (3) To what extent can quantum phenomena hinder time’s
arrow? In each branch of research, we found a tension, or an apparent
conflict. Such conflicts fuel physics. So, from 2025 to 2028, we are
resolving those tensions. Also, we are addressing another angle on
thermodynamic emergence: (4) How does quantum gravity give rise to
smooth space-time? We leverage abstract theory, numerical simulations,
and experimental collaborations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pursuing this research unifies our team into a Maryland-based hub, a
center for North American quantum thermodynamics. We partner with
international institutions to form a global network. Our events include
annual gatherings and seminars. Also, we engage the general public in the
adventure of quantum thermodynamics through a quantum-steampunk
creative-writing course, a quantum-steampunk creative-writing contest,
contributions to mainstream media, public lectures, and blog posts.
Uncovering how everyday phenomena emerge from microscopic quantum
dynamics, we are illuminating fundamental physics while establishing a
lodestone for North American quantum thermodynamics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Quantum Thermodynamics and Decoherence</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2026/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2026 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is no registration fee, but registration is required.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul class="cta-group">
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeXJ_UHPafzc32ICC3uWoOWQ4Wy4hxl5V--ZhBBzlno6goeZg/viewform" class="btn btn-primary px-3 py-3">Please register here.&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A collaboration between the &lt;a href="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Maryland Quantum-Thermodynamics Hub&lt;/a> and the University of Rochester &lt;a href="https://www.sas.rochester.edu/quantum/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Center for Coherence and Quantum Science&lt;/a> (CQS)&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="keynote-speaker">Keynote Speaker&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Novelist and Scientific American contributing editor &lt;a href="https://www.markalpert.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Alpert&lt;/a>, author of &lt;em>Final Theory&lt;/em>, &lt;em>The Omega Theory&lt;/em>, and other science-inspired novels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Book cover" srcset="
/event/symposium-2026/cover_omega_theory_hu887d2358b64d85b2a898d063f8a0f729_51810_87fd5d6f465e0854885ffbe83567efb1.webp 400w,
/event/symposium-2026/cover_omega_theory_hu887d2358b64d85b2a898d063f8a0f729_51810_7f0c61de1651f6a46f745474e10ba366.webp 760w,
/event/symposium-2026/cover_omega_theory_hu887d2358b64d85b2a898d063f8a0f729_51810_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2026/cover_omega_theory_hu887d2358b64d85b2a898d063f8a0f729_51810_87fd5d6f465e0854885ffbe83567efb1.webp"
width="336"
height="500"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="invited-science-speakers">Invited Science Speakers&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://jfi.uchicago.edu/~tten/Chile/Sergio%27s%20site/fbarra.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Felipe Barra&lt;/a> (University of Chile)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://physics.uconn.edu/person/lea-ferreira-dos-santos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lea Ferreira dos Santos&lt;/a> (University of Connecticut)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ece.umd.edu/clark/faculty/1891/Saikat-Guha" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Saikat Guha&lt;/a> (University of Maryland)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.giulia-rubino.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Giulia Rubino&lt;/a> (University of Bristol)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bayan Karimi (University of Chicago)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://w3.physics.arizona.edu/people/charles-stafford" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Charles Stafford&lt;/a> (University of Arizona)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.engineering.cornell.edu/people/mark-wilde/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mark Wilde&lt;/a> (Cornell University)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="poster-session">Poster Session&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A poster session will include a competition for student and postdoctoral entrants. &lt;a href="https://www.fcatalyst.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Fidelity Center for Applied Technology&lt;/a> is offering prizes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="travel-scholarships">Travel Scholarships&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Early-career researchers will be able to apply for travel grants sponsored by &lt;a href="https://www.normalcomputing.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Normal Computing&lt;/a>. Check back later for details.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- ---
# Titles and Abstracts
---
## Jacob A. Barandes
*Harvard University*
### Statistical Mechanics with Stochastic Dynamics
There are a number of deep questions at the foundations of statistical mechanics, including the rigorous justification of its probability distributions, the limitations of ergodicity, the origins of the thermodynamic arrow of time, and the precise intertheoretic reduction of classical thermodynamics to quantum mechanics. In this talk, I will argue that a new approach to formulating quantum theory in terms of ‘indivisible’ stochastic dynamics may provide new resources for answering these questions, as well as for related problems, like making microphysical sense of causal influences. By employing this new indivisible formulation, I will also show how to use simple thermodynamic systems to build real-world analog models of quantum systems, like qubits.
---
## Ceren B. Dag
*Indiana University Bloomington*
### Quantum scarring in many-body quantum systems
Quantum scars, introduced within the context of single-particle billiard model in 1984, are quantum eigenstates with an enhanced probability density around an unstable periodic orbit (UPO) in a chaotic phase space. Recently, nonthermal many-body eigenstates embedded in an otherwise thermal spectrum have been identified as a many-body generalization of quantum scars. This concept, however, is not associated to a chaotic phase space, and hence the connection between the single- and many-body notions of quantum scars had remained incomplete. In this talk, I will present the first quantum many-body scars originating from UPOs of a chaotic phase space in different spin models. These states verify the eigenstate thermalization hypothesis, and we thus refer to them as thermal quantum many-body scars. While they do not preclude thermalization, their spectral structure featuring approximately equispaced towers of states yields an anomalous oscillatory dynamics preceding thermalization for wavepackets initialized on a UPO. I will highlight a particular spin-1 chain which hosts both types of scars, thermal and nonthermal where the latter is associated with stable periodic orbits. Time permitting, I will also provide evidence for the ubiquity of scarred quantum eigenstates in a generic spin-1/2 chain, and how scarring makes the system more likely to be found on an orbit it was initialized on, retaining a memory of its past.
Physical Review Letters 132 (2), [020401](https://journals.aps.org/prl/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.020401) (2024). &lt;/br>
Physical Review B 110 (14), [144302](https://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.110.144302) (2024).&lt;/br>
arXiv:[2408.10301](https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10301)
---
## Alaina Green
*University of Maryland*
### The Trapped Ion Toolkit for Quantum Thermodynamics
The precise control of quantized degrees of freedom available in trapped ion quantum computers/simulators have already been leveraged to perform seminal projects of experimental quantum thermodynamics (QTD). In this talk I will describe the standard trapped ion toolkit for quantum simulation - the contemporary ways in which both the ion's valence electronic state and the ions harmonic motion (i.e. phonons) are controlled in the lab. Additionally, I will present a short description of the early QTD experiments which used this toolkit and preview the means of expanding the toolkit, presently being pursued in my lab and others. Time allowing, I will briefly compare trapped ion simulators to other simulation platforms and/or comment on trapped ion quantum computers as tools for experimental QTD.
---
## Eduardo Martin-Martinez
*University of Waterloo*
### Towards Quantum Field Thermodynamics: Observational Entropy and Operational Definitions of Work and Heat
We will review the notions of internal energy and work distributions in quantum field theory (QFT), highlighting the limitations of extending standard thermodynamic definitions—many of them originally developed for finite-dimensional quantum systems—to the infinite-dimensional, local setting of QFT. Following this review, we will argue for a reformulation of thermodynamic concepts such as work, heat, and entropy within the algebraic framework of von Neumann algebras, which is the language that naturally encodes the operational and localization structure of QFT. This shift is essential for constructing a physically meaningful extension of quantum thermodynamics beyond finite systems, particularly in addressing the inadequacy of the von Neumann entropy to capture thermodynamic behavior in scenarios involving coarse-grained observations or limited resolution. Within this framework, we introduce a generalization of observational entropy for systems with a richer set of controllable degrees of freedom.
---
## Iman Marvian
*Duke University*
### Coherence Distillation, Fisher Information Metrics, and Energy-Conserving Quantum Circuits
In the first part of this talk, I will discuss the distillation of coherent states from multiple coherent thermal states under general phase-insensitive operations--protocols that combine several copies of noisy coherent states to obtain a single mode in a less noisy state, i.e., at a lower temperature. I will present the optimal protocol that yields the closest output to the desired coherent state and show that the error is governed by the so-called RLD Fisher information metric, thereby providing an operational interpretation of this quantity.
In the second part, I will discuss an ongoing project on energy-conserving quantum circuits, i.e., circuits that conserve the intrinsic Hamiltonian of qubits. I will explain how general energy-conserving unitary transformations can be implemented using energy-conserving interactions, such as the XY interaction, provided that one can employ a single ancillary qubit that acts as a catalyst.
---
## Niklas Muller
*University of New Mexico*
### From Quantum Scars to Advantage: Quantum Simulating Thermalization
---
## John Nichol
*University of Rochester*
### The thermodynamics of semiconductor quantum dots
Electrons in semiconductor quantum dots offer a versatile platform for exploring a wide variety of physical concepts, including thermodynamics. I will review the basic ideas of thermodynamics in the context of semiconductor quantum dots, provide an overview of recent results and open questions in this area, and discuss current experiments in my group in this area.
---
## Ricardo Román-Ancheyta
*Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México*
### Heat Transport and Rectification via Quantum Statistical and Coherence Asymmetries
The repeated system-bath interaction model, also known as the quantum collision model, remains a versatile framework for studying quantum heat transport phenomena. This approach allows us to identify the fundamental symmetries that govern these behaviors. I will illustrate this by discussing our recent work, in which we thoroughly investigated thermal rectification (asymmetric heat conduction) in scenarios similar to single atomic junctions, quantum thermal machines, quantum thermalization, and coherence generation in the steady state through composite interactions.
---
-->
&lt;!-- &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #7f6c34; padding: .3rem; border-radius: 8px; background-color: #f9e09e; margin-top: 1em; text-align: center; color: #522602;">
&lt;strong>🚧 More information to come soon. 🚧&lt;/strong>
&lt;/div> --></description></item><item><title>Fluctuation theorems for autonomous work</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-jarzynski-deffner-rahav/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-jarzynski-deffner-rahav/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Metrological symmetries in singular quantum multi-parameter estimation</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-mihailescu-sarkar-bayat-campbell-mitchell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-mihailescu-sarkar-bayat-campbell-mitchell/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Non-Markovian spontaneous emission in a tunable cavity formed by atomic mirrors</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-das-solano-sinha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-das-solano-sinha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Decoherence and Brownian motion of a polarizable particle near a surface</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-jakubec-jarzynski-sinha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-jakubec-jarzynski-sinha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Suppressing excitations in the nonlinear Landau-Zener model</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-deffner-campbell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-deffner-campbell/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nonequilibrium steady states in multi-bath quantum collision models</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-mcelvogue-mitchell-landi-etal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-mcelvogue-mitchell-landi-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kubo-Martin-Schwinger relation for energy eigenstates of SU(2)-symmetric quantum many-body systems</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-noh-lasek-leschack-etal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-noh-lasek-leschack-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effect of Self-Interaction on Feynman's Interpretation of the Lamb Shift</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-milonni-berman-sinha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-milonni-berman-sinha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Master equation formulations for continuous feedback in quantum systems</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-desousa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-desousa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Numerical evidence for the non-Abelian eigenstate thermalization hypothesis and a non-Abelian fluctuation-dissipation theorem</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-leschack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-leschack/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Maryland Quantum-Thermodynamics Symposium 2025 and first annual Quantum Workshop at UMBC</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2025/</guid><description>&lt;ul class="cta-group">
&lt;li>
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeDL4aFxYBVjcpVj1-zKGDu6b0RIw0wRr666aJ-sYAXvTZPCw/viewform?usp=sharing" class="btn btn-primary px-3 py-3">Register here&lt;/a>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Co-hosted by the &lt;a href="https://qsi.umbc.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Quantum Science Institute&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="invited-speakers">Invited Speakers&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.jacobbarandes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jacob A. Barandes&lt;/a> (Harvard University)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://physics.indiana.edu/about/directory/all-faculty-scientists/dag-ceren.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ceren B. Dag&lt;/a> (Indiana University Bloomington)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://jqi.umd.edu/people/alaina-green" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alaina Green&lt;/a> (University of Maryland)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/emmfis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eduardo Martin-Martinez&lt;/a> (University of Waterloo)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://ece.duke.edu/people/iman-marvian/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Iman Marvian&lt;/a> (Duke University)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://physics.unm.edu/people/faculty/niklas-mueller.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Niklas Muller&lt;/a> (University of New Mexico)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.sas.rochester.edu/pas/people/faculty/nichol_john/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John Nichol&lt;/a> (University of Rochester)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://web.siia.unam.mx/siia-publico/c/busqueda_individual.php?id=119894" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ricardo Román-Ancheyta&lt;/a> (Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="titles-and-abstracts">Titles and Abstracts&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="jacob-a-barandes">Jacob A. Barandes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Harvard University&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="statistical-mechanics-with-stochastic-dynamics">Statistical Mechanics with Stochastic Dynamics&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>There are a number of deep questions at the foundations of statistical mechanics, including the rigorous justification of its probability distributions, the limitations of ergodicity, the origins of the thermodynamic arrow of time, and the precise intertheoretic reduction of classical thermodynamics to quantum mechanics. In this talk, I will argue that a new approach to formulating quantum theory in terms of ‘indivisible’ stochastic dynamics may provide new resources for answering these questions, as well as for related problems, like making microphysical sense of causal influences. By employing this new indivisible formulation, I will also show how to use simple thermodynamic systems to build real-world analog models of quantum systems, like qubits.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="ceren-b-dag">Ceren B. Dag&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Indiana University Bloomington&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="quantum-scarring-in-many-body-quantum-systems">Quantum scarring in many-body quantum systems&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Quantum scars, introduced within the context of single-particle billiard model in 1984, are quantum eigenstates with an enhanced probability density around an unstable periodic orbit (UPO) in a chaotic phase space. Recently, nonthermal many-body eigenstates embedded in an otherwise thermal spectrum have been identified as a many-body generalization of quantum scars. This concept, however, is not associated to a chaotic phase space, and hence the connection between the single- and many-body notions of quantum scars had remained incomplete. In this talk, I will present the first quantum many-body scars originating from UPOs of a chaotic phase space in different spin models. These states verify the eigenstate thermalization hypothesis, and we thus refer to them as thermal quantum many-body scars. While they do not preclude thermalization, their spectral structure featuring approximately equispaced towers of states yields an anomalous oscillatory dynamics preceding thermalization for wavepackets initialized on a UPO. I will highlight a particular spin-1 chain which hosts both types of scars, thermal and nonthermal where the latter is associated with stable periodic orbits. Time permitting, I will also provide evidence for the ubiquity of scarred quantum eigenstates in a generic spin-1/2 chain, and how scarring makes the system more likely to be found on an orbit it was initialized on, retaining a memory of its past.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Physical Review Letters 132 (2), &lt;a href="https://journals.aps.org/prl/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.020401" target="_blank" rel="noopener">020401&lt;/a> (2024). &lt;/br>
Physical Review B 110 (14), &lt;a href="https://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.110.144302" target="_blank" rel="noopener">144302&lt;/a> (2024).&lt;/br>
arXiv:&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10301" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2408.10301&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="alaina-green">Alaina Green&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>University of Maryland&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-trapped-ion-toolkit-for-quantum-thermodynamics">The Trapped Ion Toolkit for Quantum Thermodynamics&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The precise control of quantized degrees of freedom available in trapped ion quantum computers/simulators have already been leveraged to perform seminal projects of experimental quantum thermodynamics (QTD). In this talk I will describe the standard trapped ion toolkit for quantum simulation - the contemporary ways in which both the ion&amp;rsquo;s valence electronic state and the ions harmonic motion (i.e. phonons) are controlled in the lab. Additionally, I will present a short description of the early QTD experiments which used this toolkit and preview the means of expanding the toolkit, presently being pursued in my lab and others. Time allowing, I will briefly compare trapped ion simulators to other simulation platforms and/or comment on trapped ion quantum computers as tools for experimental QTD.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="eduardo-martin-martinez">Eduardo Martin-Martinez&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>University of Waterloo&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="towards-quantum-field-thermodynamics-observational-entropy-and-operational-definitions-of-work-and-heat">Towards Quantum Field Thermodynamics: Observational Entropy and Operational Definitions of Work and Heat&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We will review the notions of internal energy and work distributions in quantum field theory (QFT), highlighting the limitations of extending standard thermodynamic definitions—many of them originally developed for finite-dimensional quantum systems—to the infinite-dimensional, local setting of QFT. Following this review, we will argue for a reformulation of thermodynamic concepts such as work, heat, and entropy within the algebraic framework of von Neumann algebras, which is the language that naturally encodes the operational and localization structure of QFT. This shift is essential for constructing a physically meaningful extension of quantum thermodynamics beyond finite systems, particularly in addressing the inadequacy of the von Neumann entropy to capture thermodynamic behavior in scenarios involving coarse-grained observations or limited resolution. Within this framework, we introduce a generalization of observational entropy for systems with a richer set of controllable degrees of freedom.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="iman-marvian">Iman Marvian&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Duke University&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="coherence-distillation-fisher-information-metrics-and-energy-conserving-quantum-circuits">Coherence Distillation, Fisher Information Metrics, and Energy-Conserving Quantum Circuits&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the first part of this talk, I will discuss the distillation of coherent states from multiple coherent thermal states under general phase-insensitive operations&amp;ndash;protocols that combine several copies of noisy coherent states to obtain a single mode in a less noisy state, i.e., at a lower temperature. I will present the optimal protocol that yields the closest output to the desired coherent state and show that the error is governed by the so-called RLD Fisher information metric, thereby providing an operational interpretation of this quantity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the second part, I will discuss an ongoing project on energy-conserving quantum circuits, i.e., circuits that conserve the intrinsic Hamiltonian of qubits. I will explain how general energy-conserving unitary transformations can be implemented using energy-conserving interactions, such as the XY interaction, provided that one can employ a single ancillary qubit that acts as a catalyst.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="niklas-muller">Niklas Muller&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>University of New Mexico&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="from-quantum-scars-to-advantage-quantum-simulating-thermalization">From Quantum Scars to Advantage: Quantum Simulating Thermalization&lt;/h3>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="john-nichol">John Nichol&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>University of Rochester&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-thermodynamics-of-semiconductor-quantum-dots">The thermodynamics of semiconductor quantum dots&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Electrons in semiconductor quantum dots offer a versatile platform for exploring a wide variety of physical concepts, including thermodynamics. I will review the basic ideas of thermodynamics in the context of semiconductor quantum dots, provide an overview of recent results and open questions in this area, and discuss current experiments in my group in this area.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="ricardo-román-ancheyta">Ricardo Román-Ancheyta&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="heat-transport-and-rectification-via-quantum-statistical-and-coherence-asymmetries">Heat Transport and Rectification via Quantum Statistical and Coherence Asymmetries&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The repeated system-bath interaction model, also known as the quantum collision model, remains a versatile framework for studying quantum heat transport phenomena. This approach allows us to identify the fundamental symmetries that govern these behaviors. I will illustrate this by discussing our recent work, in which we thoroughly investigated thermal rectification (asymmetric heat conduction) in scenarios similar to single atomic junctions, quantum thermal machines, quantum thermalization, and coherence generation in the steady state through composite interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;!-- &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #7f6c34; padding: .3rem; border-radius: 8px; background-color: #f9e09e; margin-top: 1em; text-align: center; color: #522602;">
&lt;strong>🚧 More information to come soon. 🚧&lt;/strong>
&lt;/div> --></description></item><item><title>Correcting noisy quantum gates with shortcuts to adiabaticity</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-cavalcante-cakmak-bonanca-etal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-cavalcante-cakmak-bonanca-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Uncertain Quantum Critical Metrology: From Single to Multi Parameter Sensing</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-mihailescu-campbell-gietka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-mihailescu-campbell-gietka/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quantum speed limit for Kirkwood-Dirac quasiprobabilities</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-pratapsi-deffner-gherardini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-pratapsi-deffner-gherardini/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spontaneous emission in the presence of quantum mirrors</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-sinha-parra-contreras-das-solano/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-sinha-parra-contreras-das-solano/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Emergence of $X$ states in a quantum impurity model</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-cavalcante-bonanca-miranda-etal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-cavalcante-bonanca-miranda-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Compatibility of Quantum Measurements and the Emergence of Classical Objectivity</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-doucet-deffner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-doucet-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Roadmap on Quantum Thermodynamics</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-campbell-damico-ciampini-etal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-campbell-damico-ciampini-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Simon's Period Finding on a Quantum Annealer</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-robertson-doucet-mzaouali-etal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-robertson-doucet-mzaouali-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fluctuation-induced decoherence of macroscopic superpositions</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-sinha-jakubec/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-sinha-jakubec/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Near-surface quantum sensing</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-izadyari-pedram-gassab-mustecaplioglu-sinha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-izadyari-pedram-gassab-mustecaplioglu-sinha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>No-go theorem for environment-assisted invariance in non-unitary dynamics</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-sone-touil-maeda-etal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-sone-touil-maeda-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Work and heat exchanged during sudden quenches of strongly coupled quantum systems</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-davoudi-jarzynski-mueller-oruganti-powers-halpern/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-davoudi-jarzynski-mueller-oruganti-powers-halpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stability of emergent time periodicity in a few-body interacting system</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-campbell-eisert-guarnieri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-campbell-eisert-guarnieri/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Towards enhanced precision in thermometry with nonlinear qubits</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-deffner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thermally driven quantum refrigerator autonomously resets superconducting qubit</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-aamir-suria-guzman-etal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2025-aamir-suria-guzman-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thermodynamic perspective on quantum fluctuations</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-sone-sinha-deffner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-sone-sinha-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Properties and applications of the Kirkwood-Dirac distribution</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-arvidsson-etal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-arvidsson-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quantum thermodynamics of nonequilibrium processes in lattice gauge theories</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-davoudi-jarzynski-mueller-oruganti-powers-halpern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-davoudi-jarzynski-mueller-oruganti-powers-halpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Numerical evidence for the non-Abelian eigenstate thermalization hypothesis</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-lasek-noh-leschack-halpern/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-lasek-noh-leschack-halpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Maxwell's demon across the quantum-to-classical transition</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-annby-andersson-bhattacharyya-bakhshinezhad-holst-sousa-jarzynski/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-annby-andersson-bhattacharyya-bakhshinezhad-holst-sousa-jarzynski/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Key issues review: useful autonomous quantum machines</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-guzman-erker-gasparinetti-huber-halpern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-guzman-erker-gasparinetti-huber-halpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Non-Abelian transport distinguishes three usually equivalent notions of entropy production</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-upadhyaya-braasch-landi-yungerhalpern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-upadhyaya-braasch-landi-yungerhalpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hybrid quantum-classical computation for automatic guided vehicles scheduling</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-smierzchalski-paw%C5%82owski-przybysz-pawela-pucha%C5%82a-koniorczyk-gardas-deffner-domino/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-smierzchalski-paw%C5%82owski-przybysz-pawela-pucha%C5%82a-koniorczyk-gardas-deffner-domino/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nonequilibrium statistical physics of feedback-controlled and autonomous information-thermodynamic systems</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-bhattacharyya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-bhattacharyya/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Information dynamics in controlled and uncontrolled quantum systems</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-carolan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-carolan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Operator growth and spread complexity in open quantum systems</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-carolan-kiely-campbell-deffner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-carolan-kiely-campbell-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quantum Thermodynamics (QTD) Conference 2024</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/qtd-conference-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/qtd-conference-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>The conference will take place at the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/1oopBhs7BQPviSR39" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Edward St. John Learning and Teaching Center&lt;/a>. For more detail, please visit the &lt;a href="https://qtd2024.umd.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conference website&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conditional quantum thermometry–enhancing precision by measuring less</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-sone-soares-pinto-deffner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-sone-soares-pinto-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Estimation of Hamiltonian parameters from thermal states</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-garcia-pintos-bharti-bringewatt-dehghani-ehrenberg-halpern-gorshkov/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-garcia-pintos-bharti-bringewatt-dehghani-ehrenberg-halpern-gorshkov/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Energetic cost for speedy synchronization in non-Hermitian quantum dynamics</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-aifer-thingna-deffner/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-aifer-thingna-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Information scrambling–a quantum thermodynamic perspective</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-touil-deffner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-touil-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On the Baltimore Light RailLink into the quantum future</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-domino-doucet-robertson-gardas-deffner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-domino-doucet-robertson-gardas-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Simon's algorithm in the NISQ cloud</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-robertson-doucet-spicer-deffner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-robertson-doucet-spicer-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Steady-state entanglement generation via Casimir-Polder interactions</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-izadyari-pusuluk-sinha-mustecapl%C4%B1oglu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-izadyari-pusuluk-sinha-mustecapl%C4%B1oglu/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Delay-induced spontaneous dark state generation from two distant excited atoms</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-giron-solano-sinha-barberisblostein/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-giron-solano-sinha-barberisblostein/</guid><description/></item><item><title>First passage times for continuous quantum measurement currents</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-kewming-kiely-campbell-landi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-kewming-kiely-campbell-landi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Multiparameter critical quantum metrology with impurity probes</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-mihailescu-bayat-campbell-mitchell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-mihailescu-bayat-campbell-mitchell/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fluctuation-induced forces on nanospheres in external fields</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-jakubec-solano-delic-sinha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-jakubec-solano-delic-sinha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Continuous feedback protocols for cooling and trapping a quantum harmonic oscillator</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-sousa-bakhshinezhad-annby-andersson-samuelsson-potts-jarzynski/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-sousa-bakhshinezhad-annby-andersson-samuelsson-potts-jarzynski/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quantum information scrambling in two-dimensional Bose-Hubbard lattices</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-tripathy-touil-gardas-deffner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-tripathy-touil-gardas-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fisher information rates in sequentially measured quantum systems</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-oconnor-campbell-landi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-oconnor-campbell-landi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scalar QED model for polarizable particles in thermal equilibrium or in hyperbolic motion in vacuum</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-sinha-milonni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-sinha-milonni/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Efficiency optimization in quantum computing: balancing thermodynamics and computational performance</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-smierzchalski-mzaouali-deffner-gardas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-smierzchalski-mzaouali-deffner-gardas/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effects of noncommuting charges in quantum information and thermodynamics</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-majidy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2024-majidy/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pointer states and quantum Darwinism with two-body interactions</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-duruisseau-touil-deffner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-duruisseau-touil-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Detailed fluctuation theorem from the one-time measurement scheme</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-maeda-holdsworth-deffner-sone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-maeda-holdsworth-deffner-sone/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Quantum electrodynamics with time-varying dielectrics</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-prabhu-parra-contreras-goldschmidt-sinha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-prabhu-parra-contreras-goldschmidt-sinha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Noncommuting conserved charges in quantum thermodynamics and beyond</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-majidy-lasek-upadhyaya-kalev-halpern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-majidy-lasek-upadhyaya-kalev-halpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Characterisation and optimality of open quantum system dynamics</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-oconnor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-oconnor/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Critical phase and spin sharpening in SU(2)-symmetric monitored quantum circuits</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-majidy-agrawal-gopalakrishnan-potter-vasseur-yungerhalpern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-majidy-agrawal-gopalakrishnan-potter-vasseur-yungerhalpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Exchange fluctuation theorems for strongly interacting quantum pumps</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-sone-soarespinto-deffner/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-sone-soarespinto-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thermodynamics of quantum information in noisy polarizers</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-aifer-myers-deffner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-aifer-myers-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Deterministic quantum computation with one-clean-qubit model as an open quantum system</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-xuereb-campbell-goold-xuereb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-xuereb-campbell-goold-xuereb/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Experimental observation of thermalization with noncommuting charges</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-kranzl-etal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-kranzl-etal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thermometry of quantum environments with impurity probes</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-mihailescu-campbell-mitchell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-mihailescu-campbell-mitchell/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Entropy of the quantum work distribution</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-kiely-oconnor-fogarty-landi-campbell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-kiely-oconnor-fogarty-landi-campbell/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Maryland Quantum-Thermodynamics Symposium 2023</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2023/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="description">Description&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Maryland Quantum-Thermodynamics Hub will hold its first symposium on Pi Day, 2023. This one-day event’s aim is to cover recent advances in quantum thermodynamics broadly while fostering new collaborations. The symposium will include four invited speakers, lightning talks, and ample time for discussions. The talks will also be streamed on Zoom.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="conference-photo">Conference Photo&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Conference Photo" srcset="
/event/symposium-2023/quantum_symposium_group_march_14_hu693d695a0b678b21b814289cd241296d_4201142_3cde06eee343b98a59f36f2c8fd49763.webp 400w,
/event/symposium-2023/quantum_symposium_group_march_14_hu693d695a0b678b21b814289cd241296d_4201142_b816d05db237c76d440eca666ae3108a.webp 760w,
/event/symposium-2023/quantum_symposium_group_march_14_hu693d695a0b678b21b814289cd241296d_4201142_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/event/symposium-2023/quantum_symposium_group_march_14_hu693d695a0b678b21b814289cd241296d_4201142_3cde06eee343b98a59f36f2c8fd49763.webp"
width="760"
height="570"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- ### Registration
Please fill out the [form](https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeDzA_GcMM28n5Nyd2vrmMG8YR3LeXPSsl_jTgEJWm9KnYC0w/viewform) to register for the symposium. Virtual attendance is possible. -->
&lt;h3 id="schedule">Schedule&lt;/h3>
&lt;table class="table table-bordered table-responsive">
&lt;thead class="thead" style="background-color: #704214;">
&lt;tr>
&lt;th style="width: 30%; color: #EAE7D6;">Time&lt;/th>
&lt;th style="color: #EAE7D6;">Event&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #b9a56e;">
&lt;td>9:00 AM — 9:45 AM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Cofee and Breakfast&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #ffc8a1;">
&lt;td>9:45 AM — 10:00 AM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Welcome &amp; Overview of Hub&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #ffc8a1;">
&lt;td>10:00 AM — 10:45 AM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://physics.mit.edu/faculty/paola-cappellaro/">Paola Cappellaro&lt;/a>, MIT
&lt;br>
&lt;a data-toggle="collapse" href="#Cappellaro" role="button" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="Cappellaro">An Experimental Toolbox for Quantum Thermodynamics&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="collapse" id="Cappellaro">
Elucidating the laws of thermodynamics at their most fundamental level requires clarifying the thermodynamic properties of quantum systems, and especially the contributions of coherence and correlations in the concept of work and heat transfer. Quantum fluctuation relations have emerged as a powerful guide to understanding nonequilibrium quantum thermodynamic processes, but they are challenging to probe experimentally due to requirements of the measurement protocols and limited access to the environment. In this talk I will show how we can use spins associated with the nitrogen-vacancy center in diamond as a novel toolbox for quantum thermodynamics, thanks to the good control and coherence time, as well as our ability to tailor the interaction with a dissipative environment. As an example, I will show how we can employ repeated optical interactions to engineer a tunable dissipative channel which embodies an autonomous feedback process (Maxwell’s demon). In turns, this allows to measure generalized energy fluctuations relations in a qutrit system.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #b9a56e;">
&lt;td>10:45 AM — 11:00 AM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Coffee Break&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #ffc8a1;">
&lt;td>11:00 AM — 11:45 AM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://sites.chem.utoronto.ca/chemistry/dsegal/">Dvira Segal&lt;/a>, University of Toronto
&lt;br>
&lt;a data-toggle="collapse" href="#Segal" role="button" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="Segal">The Quantum Absorption Refrigerator as a Case Study in Quantum Thermodynamics&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="collapse" id="Segal">
Rethinking the operation principles of thermal machines in the nanoscale and quantum domain, we focus on a continuous machine operating in steady state, the quantum absorption refrigerator, and examine three key questions: (i) What is the impact of coherences within the working fluid on the performance of the quantum machine? (ii) How does the strong system-bath interaction affect the device's operation? (iii) What can we learn about the machine from current noise? To examine these topics, I will discuss open quantum system techniques, which we utilize and develop. I will then describe some results, focusing on principles. Finally, I will offer my perspective on the impact of research in theoretical quantum thermodynamics on related disciplines.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #b9a56e;">
&lt;td>11:45 AM — 01:15 PM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Group photo followed by lunch&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #ffc8a1;">
&lt;td>01:15 PM — 02:00 PM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://raizenlab.ph.utexas.edu/">Mark Raizen&lt;/a>, UT Austin
&lt;br> &lt;a data-toggle="collapse" href="#Raizen" role="button" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="Raizen"> Controlling and Cooling of Atoms using Photon Entropy&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="collapse" id="Raizen">
Production of quantum degenerate atomic gases relies on laser cooling and evaporative cooling. The latter has been the limiting factor for the available flux of atom lasers due to the large loss of atoms and the long evaporation times. Motivated by proposed fundamental tests of physics which require ultra-bright atom lasers, we developed a new approach to cooling atoms towards quantum degeneracy as an alternative to evaporative cooling. Our method relies on a self-acting one-way wall for atoms that operates away from thermal equilibrium. It uses the entropy of the photon, not its momentum, and realizes informational cooling at maximum efficiency. The method was demonstrated experimentally, and new improvements will utilize high-angular momentum states to achieve very large phase-space compression. Beyond cooling of atoms, a similar method is being used to efficiently separate isotopes for medicine at the non-profit Pointsman Foundation, www.pointsman.org. This work illustrates the utility of controlling and sorting atoms to benefit humanity.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #b9a56e;">
&lt;td>02:00 PM — 02:15 PM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Coffee Break&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #ffc8a1;">
&lt;td>02:15 PM — 03:00 PM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.preposterousuniverse.com/">Sean Carroll&lt;/a>, JHU
&lt;br> &lt;a data-toggle="collapse" href="#Carroll" role="button" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="Carroll"> Philosophical Issues in Quantum Thermodynamics&lt;/a>
&lt;div class="collapse" id="Carroll">
Quantum mechanics and thermodynamics, individually, are two areas of physics where foundational issues loom large. It stands to reason that their overlap would raise particularly pressing questions, but that specific territory is largely unexplored. I will introduce the most important foundational ideas in both QM and thermo, discuss how they might be brought together, and speculate on connections to cosmology and other fields.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #b9a56e;">
&lt;td>03:00 PM — 03:15 PM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Coffee Break&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #ffc8a1;">
&lt;td>03:15 PM — 04:00 PM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Lightning Talks&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #ffc8a1;">
&lt;td>04:00 PM — 06:00 PM&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Poster Session&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr style="background-color: #b9a56e;">
&lt;td>06:00 PM &lt;/td>
&lt;td>End of Symposium&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="directions-to-the-symposium">Directions to the Symposium&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The symposium will be held in Room 1103 of the &lt;a href="https://facilities.umd.edu/node/37298" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Biosciences Research Building&lt;/a> (BRB) at the University of Maryland, College Park. The poster session will take place in the Atrium.
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="./BRB.jpg" alt="Biosciences Research Building" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can access the &lt;a href="https://maps.umd.edu/map/index.html?feature=building&amp;amp;name=413&amp;amp;basemap=detailed&amp;amp;hideiframe=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">campus map&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Biosciences&amp;#43;Research&amp;#43;Building,&amp;#43;College&amp;#43;Park,&amp;#43;MD&amp;#43;20740/@38.989032,-76.9473592,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x89b7c6983db1236d:0xa59a6c3927bc68ed!8m2!3d38.9890321!4d-76.9431374!16s%2Fg%2F12hlfgm6n" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google map&lt;/a> to the building. On the Google map screenshot below, the red arrow indicates the BRB main entrance, shown in the photo, facing the NW corner of Hornbake Plaza. The red balloon marks the location of BRB 1103, where the talks will take place. Upon entering the building, go through the doors immediately to your right, then proceed through the long Atrium and up a small flight of steps to BRB 1103.
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="./map_screenshot.webp" alt="Google Map Screenshot" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To print a PDF version of the directions, click &lt;a href="./directions.pdf">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Non-Gaussian work statistics at finite-time driving</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-zawadzki-kiely-landi-campbell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-zawadzki-kiely-landi-campbell/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Boosting thermodynamic performance by bending space-time</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-ferketic-deffner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-ferketic-deffner/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Non-Abelian symmetry can increase entanglement entropy</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-majidy-lasek-huse-yungerhalpern/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2023-majidy-lasek-huse-yungerhalpern/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Minimal action control method in quantum critical models</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-kazhybekova-campbell-kiely/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-kazhybekova-campbell-kiely/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dipoles in blackbody radiation: momentum fluctuations, decoherence, and drag force</title><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-sinha-milonni/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/publication/2022-sinha-milonni/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/contest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/contest/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="congratulations-to-our-winners">Congratulations to our winners!&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="conventional-prizes">Conventional prizes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Grand prize:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qTODLbGMCmPoJSrBQE-3tZQEdpvwlJb2/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Creature of Ashen House&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by David Wakeham — $1,500&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>First runner-up:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ChIkCDhPuXhgnM9t4vsjxHvslRHSfyKL/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Doctor Up and Mister Down&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by Gerard McCaul — $1,000&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Second runner-up:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1QJWDWvolKL1z2qLGp2IwO3gOKlB9PDLU/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Eikonal&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by Paulo Barreto — $500&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>People’s Choice Award:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1FGNV4fgwI1UePovP4SCd9S3jGf6XMVvv/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Pursuit&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by Cristina Legarda — $500&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="idiosyncratic-prizes">Idiosyncratic prizes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For its badass steampunk heroine:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Akp2RhJPp6betZXZ4DkstdqF_bBaLWm_/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Stealing Buttons&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by Jeff Provine — $250&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For its wit and (relatedly) its portrayal of academia:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1iEiappQdmz3PZAgcRvKpaUWha0KPro6J/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Three Imperiled Scientists&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by Matt King — $250&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For its steampunk atmosphere:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1dA4D1jsvPP6BNA8jWXLWEz72J_rOF5U0/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Recurrence Machine&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by Rick Searle — $250&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>For its heart-capturing automaton:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PL2Nxcd3NSaGX-ap8Pj_2GXU8BSz68Gu/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Looking Forward, Looking Back&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, by Claudia Clarke — $250&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Read all the finalist stories below, and read about contest statistics in &lt;a href="https://quantumfrontiers.com/2023/05/01/winners-of-the-quantum-steampunk-short-story-contest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this blog post&lt;/a>. Thanks to all our writers, readers, and judges for participating!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="congratulations-to-our-short-listed-authors">Congratulations to our short-listed authors!&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Below are the short-listed finalists for the 2023 Quantum-Steampunk Short-Story Contest. Vote for your favorite story in the People&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award category! Enter your vote at &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/bwKyE8F262EWRK699" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this link&lt;/a> by 11:59 PM ET on &lt;strong>April 16&lt;/strong>, 2023.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1dA4D1jsvPP6BNA8jWXLWEz72J_rOF5U0/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Recurrence Machine&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Rick Searle : &amp;ldquo;I am a writer with a deep interest in physics and its implications for the human condition.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ChIkCDhPuXhgnM9t4vsjxHvslRHSfyKL/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Doctor Up and Mister Down&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Gerard McCaul: &amp;ldquo;I am a British physicist who works on quantum control theory at Tulane University in New Orleans. After the third incident, I am no longer allowed to discuss my interests in polite society.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Akp2RhJPp6betZXZ4DkstdqF_bBaLWm_/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Stealing Buttons&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Jeff Provine: &amp;ldquo;Jeff Provine is an English teacher at Oklahoma City Community College and graduate of the Oklahoma School of Science and Mathematics. He believes science and the arts are best experienced together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qTODLbGMCmPoJSrBQE-3tZQEdpvwlJb2/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Creature of Ashen House&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by David Wakeham: &amp;ldquo;Interdimensional wizard.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ib9cSml140Lqtbr5oUDeaeW7WCS04Ifm/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Tunneller&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Alexander Campbell: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a novice writer. I&amp;rsquo;ve been deep into sci-fi and fantasy since I was old enough to read, and I hope to make a living as an author someday.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PL2Nxcd3NSaGX-ap8Pj_2GXU8BSz68Gu/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Looking Forward, Looking Back&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Claudia Clarke: &amp;ldquo;Claudia Clarke&amp;rsquo;s PhD is in Quantum Thermodynamics which she’s definitely going to start describing as a PhD in Quantum Steampunk from now on. She writes fiction she rarely shows the world too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1wJmBYntN5xZcIV-Q4Ob9RFyBllmDWlkO/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Redacted Pages From the Journal of W.E.B. duBois&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Chana Kohl: &amp;ldquo;Chana Kohl works in Jerusalem in clinical research. Writing in her free time, her stories appear in 365Tomorrows and Metastellar. She is winner of the 2022 AnalogSF Emerging Black Voices Award.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NTAq_245Gw7wmMYtSGbnNEUKyXXSzp46/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Ai Pan&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Alex Chan: &amp;ldquo;As a tech product manager, I spend my days thinking about how existing and near-future technology can be used to make lives better. Writing allows me to theorize about more speculative technologies and their impact on individuals and broader society.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1FGNV4fgwI1UePovP4SCd9S3jGf6XMVvv/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Pursuit&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Cristina Legarda: &amp;ldquo;I was born in the Philippines and grew up in Bethesda. I hold degrees in literature and ethics and am a practicing physician in Boston. My work has appeared in Ruminate, Smartish Pace, and others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1hkBejqpMrkxfsYWUQXVVTybtgnlSkm8b/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Reprobate&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Mason Rouches: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student studying Biological Physics at Yale University. Sometimes my interests in thermodynamics are rivaled by my interests in 19th &amp;amp; early 20th century literature.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1iEiappQdmz3PZAgcRvKpaUWha0KPro6J/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Three Imperiled Scientists&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Matt King: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a certified nerd and lifelong storyteller. Currently pursuing a Physics PhD at Yale University, I am working to unravel some of the latest mysteries in neutrino physics.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ic5RIkRRBGr4fsg8rM-zegZCCp9GOdz6/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>The Final Dawn&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Nathan Suri: &amp;ldquo;I am a particle physics graduate student, trying to explore the universe from its smallest levels to its largest. I seek the truth through a myriad of lenses, empirical and creative.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1QJWDWvolKL1z2qLGp2IwO3gOKlB9PDLU/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Eikonal&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Paulo Barreto: &amp;ldquo;This is not the kind of text I usually write (I did it almost on a whim, over a couple of hours after hearing about the contest)—but hey, there&amp;rsquo;s a first time for everything!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1C9-XVNHBSeSXoFQJV3lROE-0NOUdgzt5/view?usp=share_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Raintown&lt;/em>&lt;/a>  by Katherine Wong: &amp;ldquo;Katherine Wong is an undergrad at Stanford University studying Symbolic Systems (Computer Science + Philosophy/Psychology) and English. She loves reading/writing sci-fi and collecting funky earrings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>A Message for Dr. Y.S. Sun&lt;/em>  by M.H. Cheung: &amp;ldquo;M. H. Cheung is an alumnus of the Alpha Young Writers Workshop, and enjoys stories about broken worlds, how to mend and live within them. M. H. can be found on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/@einduawau" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@einduawau&lt;/a>, and at mhcheung.com.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure id="figure-by-hannah-cho">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Contest Advertisement" srcset="
/contest/contest_ad_hu5eb578045d777af5145c11458175e0d6_136332_946c3fbf209fda0d4eff2c96dbc81304.webp 400w,
/contest/contest_ad_hu5eb578045d777af5145c11458175e0d6_136332_a058eda38d656f8079930cae22de3df4.webp 760w,
/contest/contest_ad_hu5eb578045d777af5145c11458175e0d6_136332_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_2.webp 1200w"
src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/contest/contest_ad_hu5eb578045d777af5145c11458175e0d6_136332_946c3fbf209fda0d4eff2c96dbc81304.webp"
width="587"
height="760"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
By Hannah Cho
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rules">Rules&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Each entry must…&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>be written in English;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>contain no more than 3,000 words;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>be written in a steampunk style—including, but not limited to, taking place during the 1800s (and, if desired, some time in the future); and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>involve at least one real or imagined quantum technology.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Those are the main requirements. Common-sense details are in the &lt;a href="./Contest_Rules.pdf">Contest Rules&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="stages">Stages&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Submission:&lt;/em> Oct. 10, 2022—Jan. 15, 2023, 11:59 PM EST, via &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/gr1ejeKDCBQPeBcbA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">submission form&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>First cut:&lt;/em> Jan. 15, 2023—Mar. 15, 2023. &lt;br />
The &lt;a href="#leadership">leadership team&lt;/a> will choose 15 finalists.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Finalist judging:&lt;/em> Mar. 16, 2023—Apr. 16, 2023 &lt;br/>
The &lt;a href="#judges">judges&lt;/a> will select winners. The finalists will be posted online, where the public can vote for a People’s Choice Award winner.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Announcement of winners:&lt;/em> May 1, 2023&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="prizes">Prizes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Multiple prizes will be awarded, in the form of Visa gift certificates. The grand prize will be &lt;span>$&lt;/span>1,500; the rest of the prizes will be at least &lt;span>$&lt;/span>100 each and will total &lt;span>$&lt;/span>3,000. The leadership and judges will determine how many prizes and which denominations to award. We anticipate offering prizes for categories such as Most Badass Steampunk Hero/ine, People’s Choice, Best Student Submission, and Quantum Technology We’d Most Like to Have.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-to-enter">How to enter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Fill out and submit the &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/gr1ejeKDCBQPeBcbA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">online form&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="who-can-enter">Who can enter&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Everyone aged 13 and over.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="leadership">Leadership&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Nicole Yunger Halpern (&lt;a href="mailto:nicoleyh@umd.edu">nicoleyh@umd.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jade LeSchack (&lt;a href="mailto:leschack@terpmail.umd.edu">leschack@terpmail.umd.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hannah Cho (&lt;a href="mailto:hkim821@terpmail.umd.edu">hkim821@terpmail.umd.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Undergraduate Quantum Association (shortlisting committee)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Undergraduate Quantum Association" srcset="
/contest/UQA_Gray_hu3dcf0a90a2c53509449cf6eb9c29e940_66894_d0027c8f9cd7c04b208a339c424187d4.webp 400w,
/contest/UQA_Gray_hu3dcf0a90a2c53509449cf6eb9c29e940_66894_25321be758e7f1caeb3dfa125393065f.webp 760w,
/contest/UQA_Gray_hu3dcf0a90a2c53509449cf6eb9c29e940_66894_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/contest/UQA_Gray_hu3dcf0a90a2c53509449cf6eb9c29e940_66894_d0027c8f9cd7c04b208a339c424187d4.webp"
width="640"
height="320"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- &lt;iframe class="airtable-embed" src="https://airtable.com/embed/shrXmb9QweRXyZEx5?backgroundColor=teal" frameborder="0" onmousewheel="" width="100%" height="533" style="background: transparent; border: 1px solid #ccc;">&lt;/iframe> -->
&lt;h2 id="judges" class="text-center"> Judges &lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="row justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="col-sm">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Bub_Jeffrey.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Jeffrey Bub&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Distinguished University Professor and philosopher of physics University of Maryland.&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-sm people-person">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Gilder_Louisa.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Louisa Gilder&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Author of &lt;i>The Age of Entanglement&lt;/i>.&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-sm people-person">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Harris_Jack.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Jack Harris&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Professor of Physics, Yale.&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="row justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="col-sm people-person">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Lawrence_Walter.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Walter E. Lawrence III&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Emeritus Professor of Physics, Dartmouth..&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-sm people-person">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Liu_Ken.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Ken Liu&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Speculative-fiction writer; Hugo, Nebula, and World Fantasy winner.&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-sm people-person">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Michalakis_Spiros.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Spiros Michalakis&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Outreach Manager, Quantum Physicist, and Scientific Consultant for the &lt;i>Ant-Man&lt;/i> films, Caltech.&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="row justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="col-sm people-person">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Mitchell_Emily.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Emily Brandchaft Mitchell&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Associate Professor of English and Novelist, University of Maryland.&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="col-sm people-person">
&lt;img width="270" height="270" loading="lazy" class="avatar avatar-circle" src="https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/uploads/Warfield_Patrick.jpg" alt="Avatar">
&lt;div class="portrait-title">
&lt;h2>Patrick R. Warfield&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3>Director of Arts for All, College of Arts and Humanities, University of Maryland.&lt;/h3>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title/><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/outreach/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qtd-hub.umd.edu/people/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>